<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="62"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[© Gbile Akanni,


                           April 2013 — ISBN 978-978-51801-6-9

                                       All rights Reserved
                   No part of this publication may be reproduced,
                      stored in a retrieval system, or transmitted
                       in any form or by any means, electronic,
                           mechanical, photocopying recording
                             or otherwise, without permission
                                of the publisher or a licence
                               permitting Restricted copying



                       Peace House, P. O. Box 971, Gboko
                             19, Gyado Hospital Rd, GRA,
                             Gboko, Benue  State, Nigeria

                             Pubteam@Livingseed.org
                                    Www.livingseed.org
                                    +234 703 03636 59






                            Peacehousepress@livingseed.org
                                     +234 809 148 8852]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[While  You Are Young    5
                           The Prime Time     9
                         The Raging Battle!   13
                        Peculiar Challenges   17
               Lamenting The Wasted Youth     23
                          The Battle Begins   29
                       The Enemy's Targets    33

                        The choice is yours   43
              Young Men Of Wrong Choices      47
               Response Determines Future     55]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[Page 4]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[While You
           Are Young


            was  invited  to  preach  at  a  Professor's
           daughter's wedding, in  1985.
           You  can  imagine  the  cream  of  the  society
       seated;  Professors,  Doctors,  Businessmen  and
       women,  high  ranking  Government  officials  etc.  -
       men and women who seemed to have made their
       mark in the world.

       As I brought the word of life to the young couple,
       who were just starting their journey into marriage, I
       set  forth  principle  after  principle  of  how  God
       designed  the  home  to  work.  God  enabled  me  to
       bring out the message with clear instructions and
       illustrations.
       He also permitted me to share living testimonies of
       how  the  principles  have  worked  both  in  my
       personal  experience  and  in  several  homes  I  have
       been privileged to watch over.]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[Page 6

       After the service, two people came to me, one after
       the other. The first man, quite elderly, looked at me,
       adjusted his spectacles and said . . .
          "Young man I wish I met you in 1943. If I
          had met you forty-two years ago and heard
          what  you  are  preaching  now,  I  would  not
          have been what I am today. What can I do
          now? I have spoilt my life, I have wasted my
          marriage,  and  I  don’t  even  know  where  to
          begin again. I wish I had met you then."
          "Where  were  you,  when  I  just  married?"
          he added  rhetorically.
       I  did  not  answer,  I  could  not.  I  knew  he  was  not
       expecting  an  answer  from  me.  As  I  stood  there
       looking at an old man shedding tears, I also wished I
       had met him then!

       The  second  person  was  the  wife  of  one  of  the
       University Professors. She walked up to me, looked
       at me with eyes full of regret and said . . .
          "Well, I thank you for all you have said. For
          me it is too late but I am going to buy the
          tapes for my daughter so that she will not go
          the way I went."

       All through the day, I could not get their words out
       of my mind. So, a man can hear the word of God too
       late! So, wrong choices made early in life may never]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Page 7
       be correctable again later on in life!
       I  suddenly  realized  the  great  privilege  of  being
       young. I realized the prime value of being a youth. It
       became  clear  that  there  are  things  that  must
       happen to me as a youth if I will not live my adult
       years in regret.]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Page 8]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[The
            Prime Time


              he  time  of  youth  is  the  prime  time  in
             anyone’s  life.  It  is  a  great  privilege  to  be
             young. Many old people do envy the youth.
       They wish they could return to being young again;
       and that is why they try to do whatever they can, to
       look young.
       Unfortunately, being young comes only  once in a
       lifetime. No one can be young more than once. As a
       lady, you cannot be 'sweet sixteen' more than once.
       Once you pass the age of sixteen, it is clear that you
       can never be sixteen again.

       However,  the  time  of  youth  is  also  the  period  of
       making  choices.  And the choices at this prime time
       of life are such that make indelible marks on one’s
       life and destiny.
       There is a battle going on in this world concerning
       young  people  and  it  is  all  about  influencing  their]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Page 10

       choices.
          Choices that will mark your life out for greatness
          and glory are made when you are young.

       If you meet an accomplished old man, prosperous
       and  celebrated,  enjoying  the  care  of  his  equally
       successful  children,  it  did  not  just  happen
       somewhere  in  his  old  age.  It  is  the  product  of  a
       series  of  wise  choices  that  he  made  while  in  his
       teens and twenties.
          On the other hand, choices that will predispose
          you  to  perpetual  defeat  and  failure  are  also
          made when you are young.
       Whatever wrong things we see in an old man today,
       most  likely  happened  because  of  the  choices  he
       made when he was young.
       If  you  see  an  old  woman  whose  marriage  has
       scattered  and  she  is  being  pushed  between  one
       man and another, it is not likely to be due to choices
       she made when she has become that old. She laid
       the foundation to be that kind of woman when she
       was young!
          The unfortunate thing about these choices is
          that whether they were made consciously or
          unconsciously, they are often irreversible.
       The time of youth is not only one of making choices;]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Page 11
       it is also the time for laying the foundation for every
       aspect  of  future  life.    It is at this time that you lay
       the foundation for your career in life, your marriage
       and your destiny. In  fact, everything that you  will
       become in life is being founded now in the time of
       your youth.
       It is a time of tremendous strength and energy, a
       time of  freshness.  It is the time all your nerves and
       instincts are seeking the strongest expression. The
       direction  you  'plough'  them,  now  that  you  are
       young, determines the destination you will 'reap' in
       the years ahead. This time of your youth is a very
       crucial time that determines what happens for the
       rest of your life.
       The time of one’s youth is also the time of warfare.
       This is when you pitch your tent on whichever side
       you choose in the battle of life.
          And you either choose God or Satan.

       It is in this period of your life when you are called
       'the youth' that you make that choice.

       God is out, mercifully looking for you, so that you
       will  make  Him  your  choice;  but  the  devil  is  also
       fighting hard, to make sure he has you on his side.
       That  is  why  the  counsel  of  the  word  of  God  to
       anyone who is a youth is;]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Eccl. 12:1 (NET)

       If  you  overcome  in  this  battle  now  that  you  are
       young  and  make  the  Lord  your  choice,  you  will
       always overcome in every sphere of your life.



























         Page 12]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[The Raging
                    Battle!


             here is a raging battle! . . . between God and
             the devil; and it is all about you!
             Both God and the devil equally believe in the
       young man and in the young woman. If you get into
       the  heart  of  the  devil  today,  the  greatest
       mobilization he is making is for the young person to
       become his own.

       And if you are able to get to heaven to look into the
       very heart of God,  it will surprise you that  God is
       tremendously yearning for the young person.   The
       Bible says,








                                 Psalms 127:4-5 (KJV)]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Page 14

       That scripture even says ‘happy is the man’, and not
       ‘happy is the God’. This is to tell you that apart from
       God and the devil, even a man is happy if his quiver
       is full of young people.
          The  real  battles  of  this  world  are  about
          capturing  the  young  people.  When  you
          understand  this  battle,  then  you  will
          understand  why  you  are  facing  all  the
          conflicts that you do as a young person. You
          will understand why you are confronted with
          all the challenges that are coming your way.
       You are at a serious junction of choice in life and you
       dare  not  throw  your  life  into  this  boxing  ring  or
       make  any  decision  without  a  definite  divine
       guidance.

       As  a  matter  of  priority,  you  need  to  come  into  a
       fresh encounter with God right away, so that you
       can hear him speak clearly to you on what you must
       do  with  your  youth,  in  preparation  for  the  years
       ahead of you.
       What makes it urgent is that there is a fierce combat
       for your life and it will either make or mar you for
       life.
          You cannot  be passive. A 'Yes' to God is a
          'No' to the devil and an 'indecision' for God is
          equally  a  'welcome'  to  the  enemy  who  is]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Page 15
          seeking whom to devour.
       As  a  person,  where  I  have  reached  in  life  today,
       including  the  wife  I  married,  is  the  result  of  the
       choices I made long before today. Whatsoever your
       destiny will unveil tomorrow cannot in any way be
       different from the choices you are making now that
       you are young.
        I urge you to read this with eagerness and serious
       determination to break forth into the supernatural
       with  God  and  pitch  your  tent  henceforth,  where
       your destiny will be helped.]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Page 16]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Peculiar
          Challenges





























                                 (1 John 2:12-14 (KJV)]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Page 18

            n times past, when I read this passage, I was
           always left baffled, wondering at the repetition.
           But  I  have  been  brought  to  see  something
       which is one reason my heart has turned again to
       the young people.
       I discovered that God recognizes three segments in
       every man’s life and each of them is quite peculiar,
       definite and different from the other. And because
       people  do  not  understand  the  peculiarities  and
       differences of these three segments, they are often
       overwhelmed by the challenges that come to them
       with each segment.
       God Himself recognizes the first segment where He
       knows people to be 'little children'. At that time, you
       were a baby, a toddler and just a little child.
       That  was  a  time  when  you  were  carried
       everywhere  you  went. You were taken to Church;
       you were taken to fellowship; and as they sang, you
       were taught the songs and  you sang with them.
       That is what characterizes the life of little children.
       It is the time of indoctrination. You do what you
       are  told  asking  no  questions  and  your  father  or
       mother  is  ready  to  bear  the  responsibility  of
       anything  that  happens  as  a  result.    All  the  child
       needs to do is just to obey. He does not worry how
       to get his provision. He only needs to cry and the]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Page 19
       parents would run around to meet the needs.
       It is the time of utmost dependence. Victory at
       that  segment  of  life  is  purely  in  being  under  the
       cloak of the parents.
       But if we will only be little children throughout our
       lives, the Bible would have stopped at the point of
       saying, ‘because your sins are forgiven you for his
       name’s sake.’
          When you were a little child, there were not
          so  many  conflicts  in  your  heart.  Whatever
          you were told, you believed. There were no
          questions in your mind. When ‘Daddy’ said,
          ‘This thing is like this,’ you believed it and
          went about telling everybody you met that,
          ‘This  thing  is  like  this.’  When  they  asked
          why, you simply said, 'Dad said so.'
       Oftentimes, even parents do not understand that
       this  is  only  the  first  segment.  So  they  enjoy  it
       because it looks so easy to bring up a child. But  that
       segment of being little children, as good as it is, is
       a very simple, basic, but short segment. After this
       there is another segment.
       After writing to people in that first segment of life, I
       thought  the  next  persons  that  God  should  have
       written to, should have been the young men. But
       He skipped doing so! And that challenged me.]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Page 20

       He went on to say, ‘I write to you fathers because
       you have known Him who is from the beginning.’
       My question then is, ‘but why did He skip the young
       man?’ I discovered again that it does not take much
       effort  to  do  the  correct  things  when  you  have
       become a father.
          Whether you repent or not, when you become
          a father, there are certain behaviors that will
          leave  you.  You  no  longer  have  interest  in
          them.  And  even  when  you  do  not  want  to
          leave them, they will leave you.

       For example, it is only when you are a young person
       that you can wear high heeled shoes and cat-walk
       around.  Look  at  any  of  your  parents  and
       grandparents; do you see them wearing such again?
       No. Even their legs cannot carry such shoes. Their
       excitement over such things has evaporated.
       There  are  many  fathers  today  who  used  to  drink
       alcohol when they were young; and they did until
       they damaged their liver. Now when you bring an
       alcoholic drink to such a father, he would easily say
       'No!' not because he has repented of drunkenness,
       but  when  he  takes  just  a  cup,  his  stomach  gets
       distended.  So  he  sighs  and  says,  ‘I  will  not  drink
       again.’

       This is because the enemy who won the battle over]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Page 21
       such a life when he was young, has collected what
       he wanted and has left him empty and emptied.]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Page 22]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Lamenting
          The Wasted
                     Youth


              here are so many people you see on the road
             now that are abandoned. Do you know why?
             The  enemy  has  already  collected  what  he
       wants from their lives and he does not want their
       empty carcasses again.
          Even though the devil will like to see fathers
          go to hell, he is not fighting too much to have
          them.  As  far  as  he  is  concerned,  he  has
          already  collected  what  he  wanted.  He  has
          sifted them like wheat and left them with the
          empty  chaff.  They  will  most  likely  end  up
          with him in hell anyway.
       As I think about this, I remember again the story of
       my message at the Professor's daughter's wedding.
       When I was called up to take the preaching on that
       day, they started adjusting their spectacles saying,
       ‘Who is that? Where is he from?’ When I asked them
       to stand up and sing, I heard them grumbling, ‘Why]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Page 24

       is he worrying us? Let him say what he wants to say
       and go and sit down.’
       They were mostly old men and women. Not many
       things excite people who are already old, especially
       if it is coming from a young man, as I was then.

       When I noticed their attitude was that negative, I
       decided  not  to  look  at  their  faces  again  so  that  I
       would  be  able  to  speak  to  them  boldly  from  the
       word of God. As I started preaching and the word of
       God began to affect them, I started hearing some
       'hmms' and some 'ahhs'.
          When you preach to old people; fathers and
          mothers, their response is quite different. The
          reason is that almost everything you say to
          them only reminds them of their past. Most
          of their years are already behind them. They
          are not looking forward to much again.
       Whenever I remember the man who walked up to
       me after the service . . . his lamentation and tears . . .
       I  also  wish  I  had  preached  to  him  when  he  was
       young like you.
       This  is  because  no  matter  how  powerful  the
       message I preached was, and no matter how much
       he wished to repent, he had made irretrievable and
       irreversible  choices  that  even  repentance  cannot
       change!]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Page 25
       Then  I  remember  the  woman  and  how  she  said,
       "For me it is too late."
          Those things affected me a lot. It means that
          it is possible for people to hear the word of
          God too late! It means they could even repent
          too late!
          That does not mean that they were too late to
          be converted and go to heaven. But it was too
          late for them to enjoy the correct life that the
          word  of  God  they  were  just  hearing,  could
          have brought them into.
       So  when  you  hear  God  saying  to  the  fathers  .  .  .
       "because  you  have  known  Him  who  is  from  the
       beginning" . . . He is talking about history, referring
       to what is already past.

       When you face fathers and elders and those that
       are old, most of what you talk about is in their past.
       You simply remind them of where they are coming
       from  and  only  help  them  to  see  where  they  can
       correct whatever remains before they go to sleep in
       death.

       Even when the Holy Ghost will come on old men,
       the Bible says they will only dream dreams. A dream
       is  often  a  recapturing  of  what  happened  to  you
       before,  which  is  being  brought  back  to  your
       consciousness as a drama in your thoughts.]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Page 26

       But when the Holy Ghost comes on young people,
       the Bible tells us that they will see visions; they will
       see things that are yet to happen.
          Yes, that is a major difference.
          Dreams are from the past. Visions are from
          the  future.  Old  men  are  dreamers  of  what
          they could have done or done better, young
          men are men of the future! They see what is
          possible ahead for them in life.


       It  is  very  crucial,  now  that  you  are  young,  for
       something definite to happen to you that will make
       you see the invisible which will define your life in the
       days ahead.
          This time of your youth is not a time to be
          cosmetic or plastic, floating through life as if
          you are in a dream but rather a time to be
          deliberately authentic and realistic with your
          choices.

       This time of your youth is the most crucial part of
       your lifetime and it is the determinant matrix of your
       entire future.]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Page 27]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Page 28]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[The Battle
                     Begins


              hen the Lord went on to address the young
             men.    The  word  ‘men’  here  is  used  in  a
             generic sense and it includes both the young
       men and the young ladies.
       He says, I write to you young men because you have
       overcome  the  wicked  one.  The  word  ‘overcome’
       indicates battle. When God, in that Scripture, came
       to  dealing  with  young  people,  the  language
       switched to that of battle. It is about the battle for
       the young.
       Repeating it for definite emphasis, God said,







       That  immediately  shows  that  someone  is  very
       greedily desirous of tampering with you as a youth.]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[Page 30

       That person is no other than the wicked one, the
       devil.
          As soon as you step into the teenage years,
          the  battle  begins.  Whereas  you  might  have
          had  some  little  agitations  in  your  heart
          before  this  time  as  a  child,  it  is  nothing
          compared with what you face as a teenager
          or as a youth.
       This time the conflicts come fierce and incessant. It
       comes with an inordinate pressure from within your
       heart.

       Have  you  noticed  that  this  particular  segment  of
       your life is a time when things happen to you that
       you yourself are sometimes surprised about? There
       are things that baffle you and sometimes even you
       are asking, ‘but why am I like this?’
          One of the first significant things that would
          sometimes  surprise  even  you,  when  you
          become a youth is how you started querying
          everything your father and mother told you
          as a child.
          Before, when Daddy spoke, you simply said
          'Yessir'. But now, when they say 'a Christian
          should  not  do  this',  you  found  yourself
          asking . . .
          ‘Why? What will happen if I do it?’]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Page 31
       When you were a little child, your parents went to
       the market and you received joyfully whatever they
       bought for you. But how many young people now
       enjoy having their mothers go to the market to buy
       dresses for them?

       If  she  does  so  without  taking  you  along,  the
       immediate response as a youth is, ‘No! If you meant
       to buy something for me, you should have asked
       me what I wanted, or you could have given me the
       money and I would have gone to make my choice
       by myself.’
       At  this  time  of  your  youth,  when  your  mother
       makes a long dress for you, the first inclination of
       your heart is to go back to the tailor to adjust it the
       way you like. That shows you have reached the age
       where you want to make your choices.
          When  you  step  into  this second  segment  of
          your life, whatever people used to choose for
          you  before  and  you  gladly  took,  suddenly
          becomes outdated to you.
          You have to choose it again for yourself.
       This is the reason why some, who were very serious
       choir members as children suddenly fell out in their
       teenage years.
       It is as if something is battling for your affection, for
       your decision, and for your choice.]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[This  is  the  age  of  personal  choices.  It  is
          usually the time of inner crises. At this time,
          there is a fierce battle for your  mind, your
          focus and your affections as a youth.

          It is the battle for the young!


































         Page 32]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[The Enemy's
                 Targets


               hy is the wicked one focusing on this time
               of the youth? I will give you three reasons.

         The first is that he has come to know that this is
       1  the time of foundation-laying.
       He also knows the Scripture that says, "and if the
       foundation  be  destroyed,  what  can  the  righteous
       do?" He knows that even fasting and prayer cannot
       change  significantly,  a  foundation  that  has  been
       wrongly laid.

       For that reason, he decides to position himself at
       this  crucial  point,  saying,  "I  must  not  allow  this
       young  man  or  this  young  lady  to  lay  a  correct
       foundation. Let us destroy it! And then, we shall see
       what he would become afterward.
       The rest of his life would be a mere patchwork, a
       matter of struggle for the rest of his years.]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Page 34

       The  enemy  wants  to  be  part  of  your  foundation-
       laying, to stick his fingers into what should be God's
       masterpiece. I pray that you will not allow him. And
       may God forbid that in your life!
          The  second reason is that he knows that
       2  there are certain things peculiar to you as
       a young person.
       This is the period of an unprecedented outbreak of
       all the virtues embedded in you.
          As wonderful as whatever it is you were as a
          baby, it was temporary. Permanence, even of
          your physical features only begins now that
          you  are  a  youth.  You  are  now  coming  to  a
          stage when whatever is formed within you is
          permanent; it is not likely to change again.

       And so,  the  enemy,  knowing  that  this  is  the  time
       that  permanence  of  character  and  direction  is
       established, desires to make a damage that will be
       permanent and irretrievable for your entire lifetime.

       When you see men that are disoriented in life, who
       have become addicted to wrong things, this is the
       segment when that permanence of addiction and
       disorientation started. So the enemy knows that the
       best  time  to  capture  a  man  is  when  he  can  gain
       permanence in his life. But if you escape his hands
       when you are young, you have escaped indeed.]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Page 35
          The  third  reason  is  that  the  devil  knows
       3  that  everything  that  will  become  your
       future and destiny is rooted in your youth. So
       he looks for you at this time of your youth to affect
       your destiny.
       This is why there is a scramble for your life. This is
       why  you  are  faced  with  all  kinds  of  conflicts,
       temptations and troubles.
       Because  you  are  strategic  even  to  the  devil;  he
       desires to use you as an instrument to do his evil
       works but to dump you later in life to face a fate
       that is hopeless.
          You  are  equally  strategic  and  as  well
          precious to God especially now that you are
          young.  God  Himself  sees  the  time  of  the
          youth  as  the  best  time  to  affect  a  man  or
          woman and gain the best part of his or her
          life. It is the best time to prepare him or her
          for a glorious future.
       Solomon  was  a  young  man  that  God  had  great
       affection for. He started out with the favour of God.
       He  prayed  at  the  onset  of  his  enthronement  and
       God blessed him with abundance of everything.
       But  he  began  to  make  experiments  with  his  life
       typical of the young. All that his father David planted
       in his heart as a child were being tested and pulled]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Page 36

       apart  as  he  felt  he  must  explore  life  by  himself.
       Listen to him describe one of his experiments with
       life:





















                                  Eccl 2:3 (Message).]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Page 37

                               Eccl. 2:10-11 (Message).

       This is the age when you feel like buying anything
       you  see  and  like.  This is the age of curiosity and
       inquisitiveness when you want to try out things and
       experience how they feel.
       This  is  also  the  point  of  seeking  personal
       expression  . . . you feel like doing it yourself and in
       any direction you want to.


            met a young man many years ago who was in a
           university far away from where I lived. He ran to
           my office when he came under the conviction
       of a wasted and thwarted life as he listened to one
       of the messages I had preached on their campus.
       He said to me,
         ‘Sir, when I was fifteen, I decided I was going
         to sleep with at least two hundred different
         women  before  I  clock  twenty-one  years  of
         age.  And  I  have  been  pursuing  that
         ambition.’
       He was a very brilliant student of Architecture but
       he  dropped  out  of  school  because  of  that
       experiment he was making with his life. By the time
       I met him, he was only about twenty but his life had]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Page 38

       been ruined. He said,
          "I  have  been trying to  repent  but  I  do not
          know how. I cannot just see girls and look
          away." He told me that, in the female hostel
          on campus, when ladies washed their under-
          wears and put them out to dry, something
          inside of him would tell him to go there and
          climb the wall and lick them.
       What a mess he got himself into! Why did satan try
       to destroy this young man? It was because he saw
       what a great man this young person could become;
       so he pressed in quickly to cut him short.
          God desires to help you and rescue your life
          now that you are young because if you miss it
          now, the devil will make such a mess of you.
          You will have become so damaged that even
          repentance may not be able to reverse it. At
          best it may just be to prepare you for heaven.
        The  mistakes  that  he  will  drive  you  into  making,
       would be such that cannot be erased. And the truth
       is, your life cannot be re-lived. You must not lose this
       battle  now.  You  must  overcome  the  wicked  one
       now that you are young. This is because even if you
       overcome later, the damage of the youth is often
       irreversible and old age will only bear the scars.]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Page 39
             or  example,  suppose  in  her  youth,  a  very
            pretty  young  Cecilia,  gets  pregnant  for
            someone somewhere first, has a baby there
       and then has a baby for another man somewhere
       else later.
        She later gets converted, becomes a Christian and
       gets  married  properly  to  a  husband.  At  old  age,
       when she is settled, moving everywhere with her
       husband, there is no way to erase or reverse that
       aspect  of  her  past.  One  of  the  young  men  with
       whom she had a baby may suddenly turn up one
       day and say,
          "Cecilia, we need to discuss".

       Cecilia may likely say,
          "No, no… you see, I am married now."

       Then the man replies,
          "Yes,  I  know that you  are married  but  we
          have  a  matter  together.  Our  son  has  a
          problem and we need to solve it together."
       The real husband will be at a loss, leaving his wife
       talking to a former lover. But there is nothing he can
       do, there is actually a matter here.

       This woman is converted, she is now born again but
       when  that  man  turns  up  and  calls  for  her,  he  is
       actually calling forth the mistake of her youth. It is]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[something that could haunt a soul throughout life.
       That is why it is very critical that you win your battle
       now in the days of your youth.
          If you do not win now, and you even come to
          win it later there will still be a problem. The
          mistakes  and  permanent  damage  of  this
          present  time  of  your  youth  may  forever
          witchhunt you.

       The devil would normally keep any ground he gains
       when you are young against an opportune time in
       the future.
       Even if you escape, he will keep that ground and in
       years  to  come,  he  will  pitch  his  tent  on  that  little
       ground beside your destiny and you will not be able
       to deny his activity in that aspect of your life.


















         Page 40]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[The choice is
                    yours


             ut  the  good  news  is  that  as  you  read  this,
             Jesus has come to meet you, NOW!!!
             He has come at this time of your youth. The
       mighty Warrior is standing against the wicked one
       over your life. Jesus Christ in all His zeal and power is
       ready to fight for you.
       He says to the devil even today,
         ‘You wicked one, you cannot touch this one!
         This is a proper child. She is born for a vision
         and  you  cannot  damage  her.  I  have  a
         glorious  future  for  her.  I  intend  to  lift  her
         very high and make her to sit with Me in the
         high places  of the earth and  later  on with
         Me in heaven.’
       However, while Jesus stands here and declares all
       these to satan so that he will not touch you, satan
       also has a valid response.]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Page 42

        And here it is,  . . .
          "If  she  were  a  child,  you  can  rightfully
          choose for her but  see, she  is  no longer  a
          toddler.    She  has  come  to  the  segment  of
          choice. She must make her choice by herself.
          Let her tell us whom she will serve this day,
          You or me?"
       Imagine the Lord Jesus Christ standing with all His
       power and the devil standing on the other side and
       you are in between the two of them.
          The  Lord  Jesus  is  saying,  "I  am  here  to
          forgive you, to save you, keep you, sustain
          and direct you to make the right choices for
          your  life.  Make  this  one  crucial  and  most
          important choice of your life FOR ME and you
          will be free forever from the damage of the
          enemy!"
       But the enemy is not silent, he is insisting that since
       you have come to the age of choice, you are the
       one to choose whom you will follow.  Young man,
       young  woman,  this  is  the  true  position  of  things
       with your soul.
       This is the fierce contest for your life.
          The  ball  is  in  your  court.  So  whom  do  you
          choose? The choice is yours!
       The unfortunate thing is that so many young people]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Page 43
       quietly choose the enemy without really knowing.
       They do this by saying quietly in their heart, "Let me
       just try all the options available to me first. I will go
       just for a while and then come back."
       If you do this, you will be giving satan a trial . . . a
       most desired opportunity to finish you . . . and for
       you it will be a dangerous and costly trial.

       The trouble is, even if you survive and make it back,
       it will not be without some form of damage. And
       the ground that the enemy gains today may never
       be recovered.

          Will you still go?
          This is the age of choice.

          And the choice is entirely yours!]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Page 44]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Young Men
              Of Wrong
                  Choices



          MY CHRISTIAN CORPER FRIEND
            fter graduating from the university and I was
            serving my nation as a Nigerian Youth Service
            Corps  member,  I  had  a  friend  who  came  to
       the  orientation  camp  as  a Christian.  He  was  even
       our   “Christian   Corpers'   Fellowship”   Zonal
       Representative.
       When we got to our place of primary assignment,
       there was a choice we had to make. We met some
       people  who  said  they  were  welcoming  the  new
       Corps members with a party.
       I declared to them that I am a Christian; I took my
       stand and told them that I have nothing to do in
       partnership  with  unbelievers.  Of  course,  they
       mocked me and laughed me to scorn.
       However, my friend stood in-between. He said to]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Page 46

       me that we should not refuse them. He was careful
       not to clash with them. I remember that they took
       him to a Beer Parlor (a bar selling alcoholic drinks)
       together  with  other  corps  members  they  were
       welcoming.

       There he ordered for soft drinks but those young
       men said to him, "How could you, a man at your age
       be  drinking  what  women  drink?"    Then,  a  young
       lady stood up among them and said, "Even me, I
       can  finish  at  least  a  bottle  of  beer  at  once.  How
       much more, a man like you?"
       My friend told me later that he became so ashamed
       that he told them to give him just a cup.
          It was painful to know that that single cup of
          beer opened the door to so many other things
          that took my friend away from Christ. There
          was nothing we could do to bring him back; it
          was terrible. He became haggard in life for
          many years until he died.
       Sometimes before he died, I went to see him. He
       looked at me and said to me, "Brother Gbile, I envy
       you." I asked why. He said, "We were together as
       Christians in the camp; and what you are today is
       what  I  could  have  become.  But  see  where  I  am
       now; I am finished. I am finished", he lamented.

       I wept, but I knew when he made that choice. He]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Page 47
       even  tried  to  repent  again  but  he  had  lost  the
       ground.
          There is a fresh ground before you right now
          as a young person, which is being contested.
          If  you  give  the  devil  that  ground,  you  may
          never get it again.

          Jesus Christ is standing at the door of your
          heart with all His power, ready to save and
          to rescue you. He knows that you were born
          for  a  glorious  purpose  and  that  there  is  a
          future ahead of you.

          But the devil’s contention is that you are not
          a robot. You must be given a chance to make
          your choice.
       But ever before he allows you to make your choice,
       he  will begin to flash the pleasure you can derive
       from all kinds of things before you, even though he
       will  carefully  veil  from  you  the  reality  and  the
       repercussions that will most certainly damage your
       destiny.
           He will flash money . . . lots of money. He
          will flash women . . . pretty, open breasted
          ladies. He will flash alcohol and other ecstatic
          substances  .  .  .  and  even  a  chance  of
          becoming  famous;  making  it  to  the  top  in
          your career while you are yet a youth.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Page 48

       All of these, only so you will pursue shadows and
       not consider God's glorious plans for your life.















                                Matthew 6:31-33 (KJV)
       Several of my colleagues chose wrongly. They have
       not died, but they are in real trouble.

          MY CAMPUS ROOMMATE

            had a room-mate when I was in my first year in
           the university. Four of us were accommodated
           in a room. We had two students squatting with
       us; so we were six.
       Early  in  the  morning,  when  I  knelt  down  by  my
       bedside,  to  pray  or  read  my  Bible,  this  my  room-
       mate  would  deliberately  come  and  hit  me  on  my
       buttocks  with  his  knee.  He  would  shout
       aggressively . . .]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Page 49
          "This is not Church! This is not Church. Do
          not show holier-than-thou attitude here."
       He would hit me again and again. And to disturb my
       concentration,  he  would  go  and  put  on  ‘disco’
       music  on  his  stereo  set,  raise  it  to  the  highest
       volume and the whole room would be vibrating.

       When I finally stood up after my prayer time and
       asked him why he was doing that, he would shout
       at me and swear to get me out of that room.
       Many  years  later,  I  went  with  my  wife  to  preach
       somewhere  and  suddenly  .  .  .  what  a    surprise!
       There, sitting in the congregation was that my old
       room-mate! He had seen the advert on Television
       that one man of God, Gbile Akanni, was going to
       preach. He asked himself whether that could be his
       old room-mate. So out of curiosity, he came to the
       meeting.
       As I stood up to preach, my eyes met his. I was so
       startled  that  I  almost  called  out  to  him  from  the
       pulpit because I had not seen him for many years.
       After  the  meeting,  I  rushed  down  the  pulpit,  my
       eyes still on the spot where I had seen him. I did not
       want to miss him. The organizers were calling me to
       follow them out, but I told them that I saw one of
       my school mates in the meeting and I needed to see
       him. As I was wading through the audience, he was]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Page 50

       also walking towards me.
          When we met, I thought he was going to hug
          me jubilantly. Instead, he looked at me with
          one sorry face and said, "So this is what you
          were planning to become. I remember when I
          used to hit your buttocks."
       Then he asked me if he could have some time to talk
       with me the following day and I agreed. When we
       met, he took me to a restaurant. I introduced my
       wife to him and then he could not control his tears;
       he began to weep. He said,
          "I wish I had listened to you when we were
          in the same room in the University. I thought
          I was wise; I thought I was enjoying life. But
          as you see me today, I am finished.
          Do  you  remember  the  girl  I  was  running
          after at that time, who used to come to our
          room?  She  has  left  me.  I  now  have  two
          wives  but  I  have  no  home  anywhere.  I
          cannot sleep here, I cannot sleep there."
       When he finished telling me the story, he asked with
       a broken voice . . .
          "What will you do now to help me?"
       I offered him Jesus Christ and salvation for his soul
       and he received Him. "But what will I do with my life
       and my marriage? How do I handle the mess I have]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Page 51
       put myself in? And see, I cannot be young again".
          "That  is  true;  you  cannot  be  young  again;
          you can only be young once in your lifetime",


          I had to painfully agree.]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Page 52]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[response
          determines
           The future


            n  this  battle  for  the  young,  the  battle  is
           between God and satan. But the battle is over
           your life. You are the one who determines who
       takes the victory as a young person. That is why the
       Bible says you have to overcome the wicked one.
       You are the primary character in this epic battle for
       the prime period of your youth.
          You have the choice to say ‘NO’ to the devil,
          to sin and to the things that satan displays
          around you, and to say a big ‘YES’ to Jesus.
          That is what determines your future.

       Perhaps the battle has been so strong in your life
       that you decide to say ‘yes’ to Jesus one moment
       but in the next moment, you change your mind and
       you are as unpredictable as the wind. You need to
       determine  that  such  instability  must  stop  right
       away, before the enemy of your soul gets an upper
       hand over your life.]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[Page 54

          The unfortunate thing about the battle for the
          young  is  that  the  devil  does  not  allow  the
          youth to look ahead. He blinds your eyes as a
          young man to think that life ends at the time
          of  youth.  Therefore  when  you  should  have
          taken a decision with the future in mind, you
          are  deceived  into  concentrating  on  the
          present.
        This  is  the  critical  moment  for  you  as  a  young
       person. If you get it right at this time of your youth,
       then it will be well with you in the years ahead. You
       will have no cause to regret or bite your fingers.
       I wish you have elders around you who will sincerely
       volunteer  to  tell  you  the  stories  of  the  wrong
       choices they made many years ago and how they
       are  still  suffering  the  consequences  of  those
       choices.
          Your life is a fresh ground ahead of you that
          is not yet spoilt but I must tell you this, as I
          told you earlier, it is being fiercely contested.
       Between Jesus and the devil, whom do you choose?
       Whom do you want to follow? The friends that you
       have  today  will  not  always  be  with  you  all  your
       years.
          You  will  suddenly  discover  that  the  friend
          who leads you into trouble will desert you as
          soon as you sink into that trouble. He would]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Page 55
          have escaped and gone his own way. He may
          even return to be part of the team that will
          ridicule  you  and  tell  the  world  about  you,
          exposing your sad predicament.
       Even though the Almighty God is beckoning to you,
       waiting with His mighty power to save, to forgive
       you  and  to  reset  your  direction,  He  will  not  do
       anything until you say a definite ‘YES’ to Him and a
       big ‘NO’ to satan. This is how to lay the foundation
       of  your  life  and  win  the  battle  now  that  you  are
       young.
          Enough is enough, take a stand!

       Perhaps you have even started to make mistakes.
       There is something you need to know as a matter of
       great importance: . . .
          the  mistakes  that  you  have  made  do  not
          constitute the real problem, the problem will
          be to continue in them.
       The years you have spent out of your life presently
       are very few compared with those that lie ahead of
       you. You still have years enough to build the right
       future.
       Is  it  reasonable  to  go  on  and  destroy  five  million
       because of the five hundred that has been spoilt?
       No! It does not make any sense to sit and weep over
       spilt milk, or an egg that has been broken.]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Page 56

       Whatever has been done till now, I wish you will say,
       like I said many years ago, "The time I have spent for the
       old man (the flesh) is enough. I will now live for Jesus
       forever. Bygone is bygone. Old man, it is bygone forever".
          Decide now while you can, that it is enough!
          The  number  of  years  spent,  dilly-dallying
          with the devil is enough. Do not worry about
          whether  you  will  have  enough  power  to
          overcome. All you need to do is to make a
          choice for Jesus.
       Take  a  stand  with  the  Overcomer,  the  mighty
       Captain of our salvation, the Lord Jesus Christ. He
       could have decided to override your will, step in to
       intervene  for  you  and  stop  the  destroyer  from
       gobbling up the best part of your life, but His just
       and loving nature will not allow Him to force you.
          Jesus  Christ  is  not  a  thief  who  jumps  in
          through  the  window;  He  would  normally
          stand at the door and knock, waiting for you
          to make your choice and willingly open the
          door for Him to come in. He will not make
          you do what you do not want to do.

       You need to make a choice; that is all He has been
       waiting for. The effectual working of the power of
       God to save and to keep you saved is available. I  am
       a living testimony!]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Page 57
           esus Christ died for you on the cross of Calvary
           to save you from your sins.  It was not His sin
           that  He  died  for;  He  had  no  sin.  It  was  the
       punishment for your sin that He took.

       He defeated the devil on the cross for you so as to
       give you the victory if you decide for Him. He rose
       again from the dead to give you a completely new
       life,  not  an  improvement  of  the  old.  He  has
       promised:











                                Ezekiel 36:26-27 (KJV)
       And I wish to remind you that it is not angels He
       came to help but weak men and women like you
       and I. If you were an angel who has never sinned,
       He would not need to help you and His death would
       have been needless.
       But it is for such a sinner like you He laid down His
       life  and  shed  His  precious  blood.  His  hands  are
       stretched out to you in mercy to forgive you and to
       cleanse you from every mess and everything that
       has ever stained your life.]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Page 58




                                  Hebrews 2:16 (ESV)
       Pray to the Lord now to forgive you. Call upon Him
       to save you. You need the Lord at this junction of
       your life. Open your heart and ask Him to come in.
       Then you will become a child of God; then you will
       have God on your side. Only then can you be sure of
       victory both now and tomorrow.
          So the challenge is yours today. The choice is
          yours  also.  What  will  you  do  with  Jesus?
          What  is  your  decision?  Pray  to  God  right
          away and commit your life and future to HIM.
          Bow with me and pray right NOW!



            nd  if  you  have  already  made  Him  the  Lord
            over  your  life  before  today,  praise  the  Lord!
            But  there  is  still  something  more  for  you  to
            pray about.
          It is time to add a permanence to your 'NO' to
          satan  and  your  'YES'  to  Jesus,  the  lover  of
          your soul. It is time to make your choice of
          Jesus an everlasting decision.

       Decide today that HIS CHOICES will be your choice . .
       . His plan and programs for every stage of your life]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Page 59
       will be acceptable to you.
          Determine in your heart that His counsel at
          every bend, turn or junction in the journey of
          life will be sweet to your soul.
       Pray about this now. Ask Him to help you. Pray with
       me the wordings of this song . . .
          Shepherd of my soul, I give You full control
          Wherever You may lead I will follow
          I have made the choice, to listen to Your voice
          Wherever You may lead, I will go

          Be it in a quiet pasture, or by a gentle stream
          The Shepherd of my soul is by my side
          Should I face a mighty mountain,
          or a valley dark and deep
          The Shepherd of my soul will be my guide.
                                  Martin J. Nystrom         .









                  Do you have any questions]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[or need any clarifications ?
                    Did you make a decision
                    while reading this book?
                      You will need help
                    in following it through!

                      Write, Call or contact
                        0703 03636 59
                        0703 768 1198
                studentscongress1@livingseed.org

                      +44 (0) 1512603136
           +44 (0) 7545569414    +44 (0) 7570289674
                     admin@livingseed.org


                     And do it now
           before the devil changes your mind!!!










         The message in this book was first preached  by Bro Gbile Akanni
        as the opening charge of the first ever Christian Students Congress
                     in Gboko, Benue State, Nigeria, in May, 2004.

                    It is available on DVD in video, Audio and mp3.]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>